<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sydney Pham</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Sydney Pham</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Graduation!</title>
      <link>/blog/graduation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/graduation/</guid>
      <description>In less than 5 days I will be officially finsihed with college! It feels like just yesterday I was sitting for the first time in my introductory general chemistry course in a lecture hall with more students in it than my entire high school graduating class. Three and a half years later I can say that I’ve learned quite a bit academically and about myself. Next semester I plan to work and travel before starting dental school in August!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Python</title>
      <link>/blog/introduction-to-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/introduction-to-python/</guid>
      <description> #import numpy as np #import pandas as pd #import seaborn as sns #import matplotlib.pyplot as plt  #df = pd.read_csv(&amp;#39;/kaggle/input/top50spotify2019/top50.csv&amp;#39;,encoding=&amp;#39;ISO-8859-1&amp;#39;)  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 2: Modeling, Testing, and Predicting</title>
      <link>/project2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project2/</guid>
      <description>Sydney Pham  Introduction For this project, I chose a dataset exploring various factors that may predict the onset of heart disease. I obtained the dataset from the website Kaggle, but the data itself was compiled from various doctors from around the world including Switzerland, Budapest, Cleveland and Long Beach. There are a total of 14 variables in the dataset, but I decided to keep the following eight: 1) age of the patient, 2) sex (0=female, 1=male), 3) cp - chest pain type experienced (0=typical angina, 1= atypical angina, 2=non-anginal pain, 3=asyptomatic), 4) chol - the patient’s cholesterol measurement in mg/dl, 5) exang - exercise induced angina ( 0=no, 1=yes), 6) oldpeak - ST depression induced by exercise relative to rest, 7) ca - the number of major vessels by fluoroscopy (0-3), 8) target - heart state (0=healthy, 1=heart disease).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EDA Project</title>
      <link>/project1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project1/</guid>
      <description>Sydney Pham  Introduction The first dataset I decided to use contains ramen ratings for over 3,000 different types of ramen from across the world. Originally titled “ramen_ratings”, I acquired this dataset from tidytuesday on Github. This dataset was created by Hans Lienesch, a man who has dedicated his life to eating and rating ramen. Each entry contains a review number, the brand of ramen, the variety of ramen, country of origin, packaging style, and rating on a continuous scale of 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2016 22:55:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/</guid>
      <description>Projects Here are some projects I have been working on:
  Project 1
  Project 2
  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>